themoneyprinciple.co.uk 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy

Quantex Research, who runs TheMoneyPrinciple.co.uk, respects your privacy and are committed to protecting it.

This Privacy Policy tells you what we do with your personal information and data about you when you use themoneyprinciple.co.uk, including:

  * what data we may collect
  * why we collect it
  * how we collect it and how it may be used
  * how we may share it
  * how long we keep your data
  * your rights and choices about the data we collect
  * how we keep it safe and secure

## About Quantex Research

Quantex Research Limited runs The Money Principle (<https://www.themoneyprinciple.co.uk/>).

Quantex Research Limited is a company incorporated and registered in England and Wales with company number 4287395.

Quantex Research Limited is registered as a data controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) under registration number ZA203267.

## What personal information we collect

**Information you may give us**

You may provide personal information to us such as your name or email address. For example, you may submit information to us by subscribing to The Money Principle community and newsletter list or submitting a contact form.

**Information we collect**

We automatically collect certain anonymous information about your browsing behaviour to help us analyse the website and our service. For example, when you use the website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed or searched for, how long you visited, and the dates/times when you accessed the website. We also collect information about actions you take when using the website, such as links clicked.

## Why we collect your personal information

We may use your personal information and data to enhance and personalise your experience and provide you with information, offers and services that may be of interest to you.

For example, we may:

  * send you money updates by email, special offers or other information we think you may find interesting and that is relevant to you under legitimate interests.
  * use the information we collect to enable us to administer the website, carry out analysis and improve the website.

## **How we collect and use your personal information**

We may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their own privacy policies.

**Contact form**

When you contact us via a contact form you need to provide your email address. Where necessary, we will respond to you via email. We will not use your personal information for any other purposes.

**Newsletter**

When you register for The Money Principle email newsletter you need to provide your email address. We use this to send you regular money updates, special offers or other information we think you will find useful.

All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we know if, and when, you open an email and which links within the email you click.

If you no longer want to receive The Money Principle newsletter, you can unsubscribe using the link in every email.

MailChimp is the service we use for delivery of email updates and newsletters. They store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to [Mail Chimp’s privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) for further information.

**Comments**

When you leave a comment, your name will appear on the site, but your email will not be shown. You can choose to leave a comment anonymously in which case emails are not stored on the website. All IP addresses are retained in the weblogs for as long as necessary for legislative, fraud and technical purposes and encrypted on our servers.

**Cookies**

We use cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser. It helps the website to remember information about your visit, like your preferred language and other settings. This can make your next visit easier and the site more useful to you. Cookies play an important role. Without them, using the web would be a much more frustrating experience.

We may use session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted. We also use traffic log cookies to see which pages are being used, which helps us improve our website. We only use this for statistical analysis and then the data is removed from the system.

We use cookies to improve your experience of using the website and tailoring operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

The cookies cannot get access to your device or provide any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. You can modify or delete cookies in your browser settings, however, this may prevent you from taking full advantage of this website.

Please note that links displayed to other sites on our website may also use cookies, over which we have no control.

To learn more about cookies, see the following websites:

  * allaboutcookies.org
  * google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/

**Tracking and analytics**

We use Google Analytics and tracking tools to collect anonymised data that cannot identify you but enables us to improve our website and deliver relevant and useful content to you. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured. You can opt out of Google Analytics by going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**Website hosting**

The Money Principle is hosted on our dedicated facilities in the UK.

**Display ads**

We may use any third-party advertising company, to serve content and advertisements when you visit the website, that we think is relevant to your interests. They may use cookies, as noted above. Please refer to their specific privacy policies for more information.

**Affiliate programs**

We may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions. This will not cost you any extra.

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if you visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications or services. This list may be amended from time to time in the website’s sole discretion.**

## Who we share your data with

We keep all your personal information confidential.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission, are required to do so by law, or must in connection with legal proceedings.

## How long we retain your data

We will only keep your personal information for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy. When these purposes have expired, or are no longer relevant, or you have withdrawn your consent for us to use your personal information (and we have no other lawful basis to use such data), we will delete such data.

If you have not used our services for a reasonable amount of time, we may contact you to ensure you are still happy to receive communications. We may also delete your personal information.

Even if we delete your personal information, it may remain on a back-up or in archives.

Please refer to other third-party applications or services used by this website for further details on their data retention policies.

## What rights you have over your data

You have rights to your own personal information:

  * Opt-out – At any time, you may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us by email to be removed from our mailing list.
  * Access – You may request to access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to us.
  * Amend – If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
  * Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data.
  * Restrict – In certain circumstances, you may request to limit the way we can use your personal information.
  * Data portability – You can ask that we move, copy or transfer your personal information.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

If you want to exercise any of your rights or you have any concerns about how we use your personal information and data, please email us at [maria@themoneyprinciple.co.uk](mailto:maria@themoneyprinciple.co.uk).

If you have made a complaint and are not happy with our response you have the right to refer your complaint to the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO): https://ico.org.uk/.

## How we store and protect your data

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Our servers are in the UK. However, from time to time, for operational reasons, we may need to transfer your personal information outside the EU. Your personal information may also be processed by service providers who operate outside of the EU. These countries may have different and/or less stringent privacy/data protection and data security rules than we have in the UK. By submitting your personal information, you agree to the transfer of your data to countries outside the EEA. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Although we do as much as we can to keep your data safe, information shared via the internet is not completely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your personal information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.
